artofmanliness.com 2009-12-30

# Legal | The Art of Manliness

### Disclaimer

**Warranty.** This site is for entertainment purposes only. While every caution has been taken to provide readers with the most accurate information,  readers are using the information on this site at their own risk. Any reliance you place on such information is therefore strictly at your own risk. Art of Manliness will not compensate you in any way whatsoever if you ever happen to suffer a loss/inconvenience/damage because of/while making use of information in this blog. Please seek professional advice.

**Updating.** Art of Manliness may keep updating old posts on a regular basis and is not bound to explicitly state all corrections made.

**Comments.** Comments on this website are the sole responsibility of their writers and the writer will take full responsibility, liability, and blame for any libel or litigation that results from something written in or as a direct result of something written in a comment. The accuracy, completeness, veracity, honesty, exactitude, factuality and politeness of comments are not guaranteed.

### Privacy Policy

This is just a standard, boring, boilerplate privacy policy, virtually identical to any other website on the planet. Legal agreements require me to have such wonderfully exciting legalese, so just bear with me here.

At [artofmanliness.com](http://artofmanliness.com/), we recognize that privacy of your personal information is important. Here is information on what types of personal information we receive and collect when you use and visit [artofmanliness.com](http://artofmanliness.com/), and how we safeguard your information.  We never sell your personal information to third parties.

### Log Files

As with most other websites, we collect and use the data contained in log files.  The information in the log files include  your IP (internet protocol) address, your ISP (internet service provider, such as AOL or Shaw Cable), the browser you used to visit our site (such as Internet Explorer or Firefox), the time you visited our site and which pages you visited throughout our site.

### Cookies and Web Beacons

We do use cookies to store information, such as your personal preferences when you visit our site.  This could include only showing you a popup once in your visit, or the ability to login to some of our features, such as forums.

We also use third party advertisements on [artofmanliness.com](http://artofmanliness.com/) to support our site.  Some of these advertisers may use technology such as cookies and web beacons when they advertise on our site, which will also send these advertisers (such as Google through the Google AdSense program) information including your IP address, your ISP , the browser you used to visit our site, and in some cases, whether you have Flash installed.  This is generally used for geotargeting purposes (showing New York real estate ads to someone in New York, for example) or showing certain ads based on specific sites visited (such as showing cooking ads to someone who frequents cooking sites).

### DoubleClick DART cookies

We also may use DART cookies for ad serving through Google’s DoubleClick, which places a cookie on your computer when you are browsing the web and visit a site using DoubleClick advertising (including some Google AdSense advertisements).  This cookie is used to serve ads specific to you and your interests (”interest based targeting”).  The ads served will be targeted based on your previous browsing history (For example, if you have been viewing sites about visiting Las Vegas, you may see Las Vegas hotel advertisements when viewing a non-related site, such as on a site about hockey).  DART uses “non personally identifiable information”.  It does NOT track personal information about you, such as your name, email address, physical address, telephone number, social security numbers, bank account numbers or credit card numbers.  You can opt-out of this ad serving on all sites using this advertising by visiting <http://www.doubleclick.com/privacy/dart_adserving.aspx>

You can choose to disable or selectively turn off our cookies or third-party cookies in your browser settings, or by managing preferences in programs such as Norton Internet Security.  However, this can affect how you are able to interact with our site as well as other websites.  This could include the inability to login to services or programs, such as logging into forums or accounts.

Deleting cookies does not mean you are permanently opted out of any advertising program.  Unless you have settings that disallow cookies, the next time you visit a site running the advertisements, a new cookie will be added.

### FTC Disclosures and Relationships

The Art of Manliness does not receive money for paid reviews of products. We will however include affiliate links where we make money if a visitor decides to purchase a product from our link. We provide the following list of sources of income for The Art of Manliness

  * Art of Manliness is an affiliate of [Saddleback Leather Company](http://saddlebackleather.com/).
  * Art of Manliness is an [Amazon](http://amazon.com/) affiliate and we include links from time to time to Amazon products.
  * Art of Manliness includes Google Adsense ads on the site. The links displayed are whatever Google thought was relevant
  * Art of Manliness is a part of the Natural Path Media ad netowork
  * Art of Manliness is a party of the Tribal Fusion ad network
